So let's start with two questions,
首先我们考虑两个问题
what is deep learning, and what is it used for?
什么是深度学习 深度学习的用途是什么？
The answer to the second question is pretty much everywhere.
第二个问题的答案几乎存在于每个地方
Recent applications include things such as beating
最近的一些应用包括
humans in games such as Go, or even jeopardy,
在围棋游戏中击败人类的阿尔法狗
detecting spam in emails, forecasting stock prices,
在邮箱中检测垃圾邮件 预测股票价格
recognizing images in a picture,
图像识别
and even diagnosing illnesses sometimes with more precision than doctors.
甚至有时在诊断疾病时比医生更加精确
And of course, one of
当然
the most celebrated applications of deep learning is in self-driving cars.
深度学习最著名的应用在于无人驾驶汽车
And what is at the heart of deep learning?
那么深度学习的核心是什么？
This wonderful object called neural networks.
最精妙的对象称为神经网络
Neural networks vaguely mimic the process of how the brain operates,
神经网络模仿了大脑操作过程
with neurons that fire bits of information.
通过神经元发射零零散散的信息
It sounds pretty scary, right?
听起来很恐怖 对吧
As a matter of fact, the first time I heard of a neural network,
实际上我第一次听说神经网络
this is the image that came into my head,
我想到的画面是
some scary robot with artificial brain.
某个拥有人造大脑的恐怖机器人
But then, I got to learn a bit more about neural networks and
不过当时学习了神经网络的一些知识后
I realized that there are actually a lot scarier than that.
我认识到实际上比我想象的还要恐怖
This is how a neural network looks.
这是神经网络的样子
As a matter of fact, this one here is a deep neural network.
实际上这是个深层神经网络
Has lots of nodes, lots of edges,
包含许多节点 边缘
lots of layers, information coming through the nodes and leaving, it's quite complicated.
分层 在节点之间来来回回的信息 非常复杂
But after looking at neural networks for a while,
但是观察神经网络一会儿后
I realized that they're actually a lot simpler than that.
我发现它们实际上比较简单
When I think of a neural network,
当我想到一个神经网络
this is actually the image that comes to my mind.
这是我脑海中的图画
There is a child playing in the sand,
有个孩子在沙滩上玩耍
with some red and blue shells and we are the child.
有一些红色和蓝色贝壳 而我们就是那个孩子
Can you draw a line that separates the red and the blue shells?
你可以画出一条线 分开红色和蓝色贝壳吗？
And the child draws this line.
然后孩子画出了这条线
That's it. That's what a neural network does.
就是这样 这就是神经网络所做的
Given some data in the form of blue or red points,
对于红色或蓝色形式的数据
the neural network will look for the best line that separates them.
神经网络可以寻找区分它们的最佳直线
And if the data is a bit more complicated like this one over here,
如果数据像这边这样复杂
then we'll need a more complicated algorithm.
我们可能需要更加复杂的算法
Here, a deep neural network will do the job and
深层神经网络可以完成这个工作
find a more complex boundary that separates the points.
寻找能够分开这些点的复杂界线
So with that image in mind,
所以记住这幅图
let's dive in and learn about neural networks.
让我们开始学习神经网络吧